Abhishek Bhaskar

Full-stack developer

EXPERIENCE

Atlys — Full-stack developer

Nov 2023 - Present

- Streamlined Visa Applications: Developed user-friendly visa application funnels with a beautiful interfaces, leading to a 20% increase in conversions.
- Built Cost-Saving Internal Tools: Developed a full-featured CMS and other internal tools, saving the company over \$100k annually.
- Developed a high-performance, in-house AI service for OCR, data extraction, and document validation, achieving improved performance, data security and reduced costs compared to third-party solutions.
- Overhauled services to eliminate latency bottlenecks and bad practices, resulting in a significant performance boost of up to 3x.
- SEO-Focused Development: Improved website page speeds for better SEO ranking and increased organic traffic (transactions).

Elevatr — Full-stack developer and designer

Apr 2023 - Sept 2023

- Built an ecommerce store builder from scratch with extensive customization options.
- Developed APIs for various features like orders and billing, inventory management, Online store, Role management, etc.
- Full responsibility of designing interfaces and UX for mobile and web apps.
- Developed all the features for web and mobile apps.

Coastr, Full-stack developer

Dec 2020 - Mar 2023

- Standalone white-labeled customer-facing booking portal with customizations.
- Dashboard and reporting solution for car rental companies.
- Live tracking and analytics solution for telematics-enabled vehicles.
- Optimized existing APIs resulting in about 50% increase in performance in most cases.
- Push notifications for platform-wide action triggers.

Ediflo (Editrac), Design and development consultant

July 2021 - Sept 2021

- Full responsibility of designing interfaces and UX for the web app.
- Built a kanban board from scratch for editors and producers to collaborate.
- Implemented a video collaboration feature with timestamp commenting and version management.
- Built a 3D collaboration prototype.

+917295084005

abhishk.me@gmail.com https://abhishekbhaskar.in

ABOUT

I have over 4 years of hands-on experience in crafting applications and implementing features across both front-end and back-end technologies. Frequently, I am involved in the entire feature development lifecycle, from initial design to final implementation, enabling me to deliver optimal efficiency

EDUCATION

2016 - 2020

Indian Institute of Technology, Mandi

B.Tech in ME

SKILLS

Node, Express, Python, Fast API, GraphQL, Postgres, React, Next, Redux, MobX, Remix, React Native, Typescript, TailwindCSS, UI/UX, Kubernetes, Docker

FREELANCE WORK

Prior to working full-time, I had about 3 years of experience working as a freelance developer. Worked with multiple clients from India, the US, and Europe. To name a few - Protofolio, Studiotale, Intry Careers, Veveo Health, Pulpcare, Apiria, and Vision studio.